<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog ✍️ on Parker Addison</title>
    <link>https://parkeraddison.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog ✍️ on Parker Addison</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 14:24:43 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://parkeraddison.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on COVID-19 and the future of teaching</title>
      <link>https://parkeraddison.com/blog/coronavirus-effect-on-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 14:24:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parkeraddison.com/blog/coronavirus-effect-on-teaching/</guid>
      <description>Amidst the doom and gloom around coronavirus, I invite you to entertain some potential silver linings with me.
With universities transitioning all courses online, teaching strategies likely won’t return to “normal” once we recover from the pandemic. But might they actually get better?
I’m preparing to TA for a now-online course next quarter, and I’ve discussed the following topics with a handful of my professors:
On teaching approaches:  Flipped classroom to teaching seem promising, but they lack widespread experimentation and support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How an Amazon Alexa skill can open the door to data-driven medical insights</title>
      <link>https://parkeraddison.com/blog/alexa-medical-insight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 20:47:36 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parkeraddison.com/blog/alexa-medical-insight/</guid>
      <description>There are a huge number of “minor symptoms” in the world that go largely unreported. Sore throats, sniffles, dull pains, chest pressures, headaches… the list goes on. These symptoms are generally not going to prompt a patient to call up their doctor’s office. Nor is the patient likely to remember them at all once their next appointment finally comes around.
Doctors wish they could change this. We’ll explore how we can change this, and examine the effects of widespread symptom reporting from a data science perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Ignited My Love For Data Science</title>
      <link>https://parkeraddison.com/blog/what-ignited-my-love-for-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parkeraddison.com/blog/what-ignited-my-love-for-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Starting by outlining the purpose of data science in today’s world, this brief talk by Parker Addison sheds light into what ignited an interest in observing, analyzing, and communicating data.
This was scheduled as the first talk in a series of Ignite Talks with a theme of discovering and pursuing career paths. Ignite Talks are like super-fast TED talks—a speedy style of presentation in which slides advance automatically every 15 seconds, resulting in a 5-minute total run time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>